Guide to the Smith Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Smith Family Papers
1894-1972
RG 5
Yale University Divinity School Library
6
(17 boxes)
The papers, dating from 1894-1971, primarily document the activities of Edward Huntington Smith and his daughter, Helen Huntington Smith in the United States and China. The Smiths were a family of Congregational missionaries in China, 1901-1950, primarily in Ing Tai and Foochow. Educated at Amherst College and Hartford Theological Seminary, Edward Huntington Smith devoted nearly 50 years of his life to running an orphanage, raising funds, and promoting Christian education in Ing Tai, Fukien, China. His wife, Grace W. Thomas Smith, educated at Tabor Academy and Wheelock College, both in Massachusetts, served as a Kindergarten teacher in the United States and China. Their daughter, Helen Huntington Smith earned degrees from Mount Holyoke College, Union Theological Seminary and Columbia University. Appointed to China by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, she taught, participated in relief work for orphans and destitute students, in cooperatives and in counselling. She served as Director of Women's Work of the Ohio Conference of the United Church of Christ and Research Consultant for the China Records Project at Yale Divinity School Library. Another daughter, Eunice Elizabeth Smith Bishop served at various Kindergarten training shcools in China, and at the China Nutritional Aid Council studying the soy bean.
Smith family
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Huntington Smith, who led two generations of his family in service to China, was born at Franklin, Connecticut in 1873. His parents, Harriet H. and Owen S. Smith, were of pious New England farmer stock. At the age of fifteen, Smith was baptized and received into the Second Congregational Church, Norwich, Connecticut. During his freshman year at Amherst College, Smith attended a Northfield Conference, where he became inspired by the evangelist, Dwight L. Moody.
After graduation in 1898, he spent several months with the YMCA in Cuba, helping American soldiers involved in the Spanish-American War. Later the same year, he joined the class of 1901 at Hartford Theological Seminary. After completion of his studies, Smith became ordained at the same Norwich church where his ancestors had worshiped for eight generations. In October, 1901, he married Grace W. Thomas, the daughter of a Methodist preacher.
The couple sailed for Shanghai from San Francisco in November, 1901, and arrived at Ing Hok, Fukien Province, the next month. (("Ing Hok" is sometimes referred to as "Ing Tai", "Yung tai" and other variations.) Edward Huntington Smith devoted his life to this mountainous district, often traveling by foot to its farthest outposts, or by boat down the rapids. He spent nearly 50 years running an orphanage, raising funds, and promoting Christian education. (This figure includes years of furlough, etc.: 1901-1950.) One of the highlights of Smith's career occurred in 1918 when he met Chiang Kai-shek, whose Nationalist Army was then engaged in fighting war lord Li Hou-chi of Foochow. (For a more detailed account see: "Chang-Smith Yungtai Memorial Fund" by Henry H. Wu. Group No. 5, Series No. 2, Box No. 10, Folder No. 39.) In 1946, although officially retired, Smith returned to Foochow at his own expense. After his expulsion in 1950, Smith spent much of his time writing on the subject of China, missions, his life and related matters. He died in 1968.
Grace W. Thomas Smith, who married Edward Huntington Smith in 1901, was born in 1874 at Pine Brook, New Jersey. After graduating from Tabor Academy, Marion, Massachusetts in 1893, she joined the first class of Wheelock College, Boston, and taught at the Perkins Institute Kindergarten for the Blind in Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts for eight years. Her work in China included substitute teaching at the Union Kindergarten Training School, and the establishment of a local kindergarten, in addition to raising the couple's own four children. At the time of her death in 1939 she was known as the "Mother of all Ingtai."
The children of Grace and Edward H. Smith continued in service to China. Helen Huntington Smith, born at Ingtai in 1902, graduated from Shanghai American School, Class of 1921. Following graduation from Mount Holyoke College in 1925, she became a Traveling Secretary of the Student Volunteer Movement for one year. She received a Master's degree in Christian Education from Union Theological Seminary and Columbia University in 1928, and spent the next two years as Girl's Work Secretary at Union Settlement, New York City.
Appointed to China by the American Board of Commissioners of Foreign Missions in 1929, Helen H. Smith spent the next twenty years teaching at the Wen Shan Girls School of Foochow. (This institution has various spellings and is also known as the Orlinda Childs Pierce Girls School. Helen Smith's maternal aunt, Eunice T. Thomas, was on the school's first staff and later taught at Fukien Christian University.) In 1941, when the school evacuated into the interior for a second time, she hid $8,000.00 in her hair and led 110 students to safety by trekking 300 miles on foot. She also participated in relief work for orphans and destitute students, in cooperatives, and in counseling at this time.
After being expelled from China, Helen H. Smith spent from 1951 to 1962 as Director of Women's Work of the Ohio Conference of the United Church of Christ. She attended the Ecumenical Institute at Bossey, Switzerland in 1961, was a delegate to the Third Assembly of the World Council of Churches meeting in New Delhi, India, 1961, and served on numerous committees. In 1963, she became "... the first woman to head a major national Board of a Protestant denomination.. ." ("Miss Helen Huntington Smith," Office of Communication, United Church of Christ. Group No. 5, Series No. II, Box No. 8, Folder No. 2.) The Defiance College, Defiance, Ohio, awarded her an honorary degree in May of the same year. At the time of her death in 1971, she was Research Consultant for the China Records Project.
Eunice Elizabeth Smith, born in 1906 to Grace and Edward H. Smith, attended college in the United States and received kindergarten training at Teacher's College, Columbia University. She served at the Union Kindergarten Training School, Laura Haygood Kindergarten Training School, China Nutritional Aid Council studying the soy bean. Her husband, Merlin A. Bishop, was involved in numerous organizations, such as the Y.M.C.A. (see: Correspondence), Sino-American Cultural Relations Committee, and the China Nutritional Aid Council, advising mechanical and structural problems. The couple had one daughter, Laura.
Grace and Edward H. Smith's youngest child, Margaret, born in 1912, married Charles E. Thrasher. Their only son, Edward Huntington Smith, Jr., died in 1910 at the age of six.
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence
II. Writings
III. Printed/professional Material
IV. Photographs
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia
The papers date from 1894-1971 and primarily document the activity of Edward Huntington Smith and his daughter, Helen Huntington Smith, in the United States and China.
Correspondence, the first series, is divided into three sections: Correspondence: Edward H. Smith; Correspondence: Helen H. Smith; Correspondence: Grace T. Smith, Eunice S. Bishop, Merlin A. Bishop.
The bulk of Correspondence: Edward H. Smith consists of letters written by the missionary to his family in Norwich, Connecticut. This material, in fact, forms a diary-chronicle touching on such topics as social change, missionary finances, education, bandits and travel. Documentation of modern China's political turmoil--the formation of the Republic in 1911, Chiang Kai-shek's entry into Ing tai in 1918, civil war, official corruption, anti-Christian activity of the Nationalist Army, 1949 Communist victory--is evident throughout Smith's correspondence.
Correspondence to Edward H. Smith is also incorporated in this section, although it is not extensive. Before going to China, he received letters regarding the Student Volunteer Movement, etc. While in China, he occasionally received correspondence from the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. During furlough years, other China missionaries wrote to him. After his expulsion in 1950, many of Smith's former students corresponded with him.
A separate section of Newsletters to and from Edward H. Smith follows the regular correspondence.
Correspondence: Helen H. Smith spans the years 1910-1970, but is not extensive. Early material is primarily of a family-nature, while that of later years is professional. Again, Newsletters follows regular correspondence.
Correspondence: Grace T. Smith, Eunice S. Bishop, Merlin A. Bishop is quite brief. Grace T. Smith's letters are to her children and in-laws. Eunice S. Bishop and Merlin A. Bishop material is housed in two folders. Additional Merlin Bishop material is available in YDSL Record Group No. 8, China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection.
The second series, Writings, contains biographical information regarding the Smith family, as well as three main divisions: Writings: Edward H. Smith; Writings: Helen H. Smith; Writings: by Others.
Writings: Edward H. Smith include several notebooks of memoirs, a diary, historical sketches, poetry, etc. and four account books documenting the financial aspect of missions. Notes regarding Foochow mission history, Hong Kong, Taiwan, etc. also appear.
Writings: Helen H. Smith contains diaries, addresses, resources for worship, material regarding the Council for Lay Life and Work, papers, examinations, and short stories attributed to her.
Writings: by Others primarily consists of memorial tributes to Helen H. Smith collected at the time of her death.
A wide variety of contents is housed in the third series, Printed/Professional Material. Minutes and Reports, dating from 1900-1965, and including that of the International Opium Society (1922), Chinese Industrial Cooperatives organized by Rewi Alley (1939-1940), is one of the most extensive sections. Magazine and Newspaper clippings, music, NCCC China Bulletin, Material re: Early Career of Edward H. Smith, are among the other categories. Box 13 contains pamphlets, including many published by the Friendship Press and many belonging to Merlin A. Bishop. Magazines, Reprints and two tape recordings by Helen H. Smith are contained in Box 14. Reprints include several works by Lewis Hoodus, Theodore Hsi-En Chen, some regarding Rewi Alley, and "Congregational Missionaries in Foochow During the 1911 Revolution" by Thomas E. Korson. Chinese language material, primarily regarding education in Ing tai, is located in Box 15.
The final series, Photographs, contains photographs of the Smith family, groups, and Chinese Christian religious art as well as several albums, and an album/scrapbook entitled "Ing Hok District of Foochow Mission, China."
N.B.: In 1914, the district name "Ing Hok" was changed to "Ing Tai", which varies in spelling.
Several maps, political posters, and a 1873 deed to a house--all originally from the Smith Family Papers--were transferred to Sterling Memorial Library, August, 1975.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence
II. Writings
III. Printed/professional Material
IV. Photographs
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia
International relief -- China; Missions -- China; Missions; Educators; Missionaries; Bishop, Eunice Smith; Smith, Edward H. (Edward Huntington), 1873-1968; Smith, Grace W. Thomas, 1874-1939; Smith, Helen Huntington, 1902-1971; Smith family; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
- Correspondence, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in the following order:
  Correspondence: Edward H. Smith (Box 1-5)
  Correspondence: Helen H. Smith (Box 6)
  Correspondence: Grace T. Smith, Eunice S. Bishop, Merlin A. Bishop (Box 7)
  The correspondence of each person is arranged chronologically. Following the general correspondence of Edward H. Smith, Box 4 contains 6 folders of chronologically arranged letters from his former students, covering a period from 1941-1966. Following this category is one folder of 1945-1946 war letters' and one folder containing excerpts of letters from Lewis Hodous to James Barton regarding the establishment of Fukien University. See Record Group 8 for additional correspondence of Merlin Bishop, husband of Eunice Smith Bishop.
  - Complete List of General Correspondents--Edward H. Smith
    - Armstrong, Susan E., 1945 Sep 24
    - Barton, James L., 1926 Jan 20, 1935 Aug 14
    - Beach, Harlan P., 1899 Feb 28
    - Beard, W.L., 1905 May 15, 1910 Sep 22, 1925 Feb 26, Apr 5, Apr 23 [n.d. to EHS parents]
    - Billing, A.W., 1931 Feb 10, Oct 11, 1934 Feb 5
    - Brayton, Miss, 1910 Apr 18
    - Chang, Raymond Gujush, 1922 Dec 28
    - Chiang Kai-shek, Madame, 1955 Dec 5
    - Craig, L.M., 1911 Dec 17, 1912 June 9, 1913 Aug 1, 1914 Jul, 1915 Apr 15
    - Cressey, E.H. (to Leger,S.H.), 1928 Jun 15
    - Donaldson, Fred F., 1924 Sep 11, 24, Oct 12, 1925 Apr 5
    - Fairfield, Wynn C., 1942 Jun 8
    - Galt, Elmer W., 1945 Nov 27
    - Hodgkin, Henry, 1921 Oct 14, 1922 Jan 21
    - Hsueh, Catherine Lin (Mrs. Donald) to R.H. Potter, 1946 Jan 16
    - Hsueh, Donald, 1945 Dec 20
    - Kinnear, H.N., 1908 Jul 18
    - Lang, Heng, 1931 Dec 29
    - Leger, Samuel H., 1925 Feb 25, 1928 June 19
    - Lin, C.J., 1930 Sep 26, Nov 13, Dec 8, 1931 May 4, 1933 May 4,1946 May 15
    - Loi Sing Lung (Manso Louis), 1949 Jan 5
    - Lucy, 1951 Mar 15, 1950 Sep 21
    - McLachlin, L.E., 1922 Dec 27
    - Northrop, C.A., 1895 Sep 23
    - Palmer, William S., 1898 Jan 21
    - Price, E.B., 1927 Jan 30
    - Shepherd, George W. Smith, Judson (from EHS and H.T. Whitney), 1931 Jan 4, Oct 11, 1932 Jan 22, 1941 Mar 31, 1906 May 7
    - Smith, Lucia Walter, 1943 Oct 10
    - Storis, Charles, 1923 Apr 23
    - Strong, William E., 1922 Dec 12, 1926 Oct 7
    - Strong, William E. Lee, Eula B., 1926 Dec 15, 1927 Jan 24, Feb 2
    - Taylor, James Dexter, 1899 Apr 8
    - Thelin, Guy, 1930 Dec 31
    - Topping, W.H., 1928 Nov 16, 1933 Dec 26, 1940 May 11, Aug 29,Oct 5, Oct 31,1941 May 25, Oct 10, 1943 Apr 9,1945 Aug 24, Nov 26, [n.d.]
    - White, Emmons, 1927 Jul 26
    - Young, Carl M.S., 1923 May 20
    - Yu, Chen Tsinig, 1926 Sep 16
  - Complete List of General Correspondents: Helen H. Smith
    - Bartlett, Betty (Mrs. Robert M.), 1961 Dec 5, 1962 Aug 27
    - Bauman, Glenn E., 1967 Jul 13
    - Blake, Eugene Carson (from HHS), 1967 Jan 4
    - Blake, Eugene Carson (to HHS), 1967 Jan 12
    - Congregational Christian Churches. Committee of the Ohio Conference., 1962 Jun 22
    - Congregational Christian Churches. General Council., 1960 May 17
    - Congregational Christian Women. Connecticut Fellowship., 1962 Apr 4
    - Coppock, Dorothy (Mrs. Robert E.), 1961 Jan 13
    - Danieley, J. Earl, 1962 Jun 20, 1967 Sep 13
    - Defiance College, 1963 Jun 3
    - Knapp, Florence (Mrs. William T.), 1962 Apr 9
    - Lee, Mrs. Lucius 0., 1931 May 31, 1933 Jan 10, Apr 17
    - Lockyear, Charles H., 1967 Sep 7
    - Lorbeer, Olive (Mrs. Lloyd), 1962 Feb 8
    - Matthews, Harold S. (to HHS); (to Dr. Thos. E. Korson); (from Carleton Lacy), 1970 Sep 23; 1970 Jul 11; 1951 Dec 1
    - Newbold, Cecelia (Mrs. V.W.), 1967 Sep 12
    - Peters, Mary Bob, 1967 Aug 15
    - Reneker, Betty, 1967 Sep 7
    - Rinden, Mrs. Arthur, 1931 Dec 26
    - Smith, Walter, 1944 May 18
    - Snyder, Don, 1967 Sep 8
    - Topping, William H., 1944 June 12
    - Turnbull, Helen (Church Women United), 1967
    - United Church of Christ. Board of Homeland Ministries, 1963 June 17
    - United Church of Christ. North California Conference, 1967 May 26
    - United Church of Christ. Stewardship Council, 1963 Nov 1
    - Wen Shan, Students of, 1941 Jun 24
    - Wood, Walter Marion, 1967 Sep 7
    - YWCA of China. Natl. Committee, 1933 Mar 6, Mar 8, Jun 20, Jul 31
    - Yates, Jack E., 1967 Sep 8
  - Edward H. Smith
    - General Correspondence
      - Correspondence with individuals listed above, 1895-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1-22)
      - Correspondence with individuals listed above, 1913-1923 (Box 2, Folder 23-49)
      - Correspondence with individuals listed above, 1924-1939 (Box 3, Folder 50-79)
      - Correspondence with individuals listed above, 1940-1966, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80-84)
      - Correspondence with students, 1941-1966 (Box 4, Folder 85-89)
      - War Letters, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Excerpts, 1912-1914 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Newsletters
      - From EHS, 1907-1950 (Box 5, Folder 92-97)
      - To EHS, 1917-1961 (Box 5, Folder 98-106)
  - Helen Huntington Smith
    - Correspondence with individuals and organizations listed above, 1910-1911, 1919-1920 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Correspondence with individuals and organizations listed above, 1927, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Correspondence with individuals and organizations listed above, 1932-1934, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Correspondence with individuals and organizations listed above, 1940-1941, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Correspondence with individuals and organizations listed above, 1963,1967, 1970,n.d. (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Newsletters, 1938-1970 (Box 6, Folder 112-116)
  - Grace T. Smith
    - General correspondence, 1902,1903, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - General correspondence, 1918-1936 (Box 7, Folder 118-122)
  - Eunice E. Smith Bishop
    - General correspondence, 1920, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - Merlin A. Bishop
    - Newsletters (to MAB), 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 124)
      See also Merlin Bishop materials in Record Group No. 8
- Writings, Series II
  This series is divided into three sections: Writings of Edward H. Smith; Writings of Helen H. Smith; Writings of Others
  The first two folders in this series contain biographical material regarding the Smith family. Edward H. Smith's writings consist of notes and notebooks, and a diary. A series of five-year diaries of Helen Huntington Smith are followed by other writing, arranged chronologically. Additional writings are found in Series III.
  - Biographical background
    - Biographical information re: EHS, GWTS "My Friend, E.H. Smith," by Arthur 0. Rinden, "The Man They All Love (Rev. Edward H. Smith)" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Biographical information re: HHS, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Writings of Edward H. Smith
    - Notes re: Foochow mission history, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3-5)
    - Notes re: missions, c. 1906-1966, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
    - Notes re: Hong Kong and Taiwan (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Notes, possibly used for general letters, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Notes taken from books, lectures, etc., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - [Sermons?], misc., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 13-22)
    - Account Books / Notebook, 1904-1949 (Box 9, Folder 23-26)
    - Diary - one volume, 1907-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Writings of Helen H. Smith
    - Diaries - five volumes, 1917-1952 (Box 18, Folder 2,3)
    - Mid-term examination in "Systematic Theology", 1943 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Mid-term examination in "Practical Theology", 1943 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Three papers prepared for Henry P. VanDusen, with note from him, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Paper prepared for D.J. Fleming re:missions, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Papers, etc. (notes about Communist takeover of Foochow), 1945,1949,1950-1959 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Papers, etc., 1960-1966, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 32-34)
    - Short stories, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 35-36)
  - Writings by Others
    - "Experiences and Awakening of Uong Cu Buoi Ing Hok. Foochow Prefecture Fukien Province, China.", 1904 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - re: EHS,written by his mother, Harriet H. Smith, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "Chinese Education", c. 1910 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "The Wisdom of the Wise Men," mentions HHS, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "My Dung Jen School", 1947 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Chen Yi Biography", 1954 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - re: Memorial Scholar ship Fund by Hwa Ming Wu, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Re: The establishment of "Chang Smith Yungtai Memorial Fund" by Henry H. Wu, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berea Bible Institute and Christian Assembly, Hong Kong," by Ralph F. Baldwin, c. 1958 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - 1 p. quotation by Prof. Chan Wing-tsit, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "A Stranger from the Orient," by Hwa Ming Wu, 13 pp. autobiography with electrostatic copies of corres. and documents, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Memories of HHS collected at the time of her death," compiled by Mary Lou Dixon and Gertrude Rinden, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "Memories of HHS collected at the time of her death," cont. (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Memorial letters to Mary Lou Dixon re: HHS; 2 other letters re: HHS, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 43-44)
- Printed/Professional Material, Series III
  The first two boxes of this series contain a variety of material organized alphabetically according to description (e.g., Addresses, Lists, Music). Pamphlets are located in Box 13, Magazines, Reprints and Tape Recordings in Box 14, and Chinese language material in Box 15.
  - Academic Catalogues, 1916, 1924, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Address by HHS, c.1951-1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Addresses by others, 1943-1969, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and Reports, 1900-1965 (Box 11, Folder 4-10)
  - Music: "Fisherman's Song" "Farmer's Song" (both Chinese folk songs), 1944 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Music-booklets: "Chinese Christian Hymns," "Camp and Conference Songs, YWCA," hymns by F. Olin and Esther B. Stockwell, 1941, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Music-booklet: "Hymns for the of the American Board", c. 1900 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Music sheets, 1939-1943, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - NCCC China Bulletin, incl. Victor Hayward newsletters, 1950-1952 (Box 11, Folder 15-19)
  - NCCC Study: "Lessons to be Learned From the Experiences of Christian Missions in China", 1951 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - News bulletins, 1952-1964 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Re: Appointment of HHS by ABCFM, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Re: Conferences and Meetings, 1924-1931, 1947 1950, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Re: Council for Lay Life and Work, c.1963 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Re: Early Career of EHS, 1894-1901 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Re: Foochow-publications primarily by ABCFM, 1932, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Re: Mid-Fukien Synod, 1944-1950 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Re: Retirement Dinner for HHS, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Papers/Essays by Sherwood Eddy, Frank Price and others, 1948-1952 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Printed Material written by EHS,HHS, inc. report re. Ing Hok mission, 1906, 1912,1919,1923,1941, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Programs, 1924-1928, 1947-1971 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Sermons/Brief Papers/Memos, 1928-1953,n.d. (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Statistical Information, 1909-1915,1952, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Misc. Re: Missions, 1-page flyers, 1910, 1927,1953, c.1958, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Misc. General, 1927, 1945, 1965 c. 1971, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Magazine Clippings, 1899-1970s, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 36-39)
  - Newspapers, excerpts from Communist, 1950 Apr-Jul (Box 12, Folder 40-41)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1940's (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1950's- 1961, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Newspaper Clippings-excerpts and reprints, 1949-1951 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - re: Chiang Kai-shek, Mme.(Soong Mai-ling), 1943 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Re: EHS, 1903, 1927,1949,1964, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Re: HHS, 1942-1965 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Lists of students, financial aid, etc. by EHS, 1904-1951, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 48-49)
  - Pamphlets documenting ABCFM work in Fukien Province (Box 13, Folder 49A)